A Guide to the Major William Henry Johnson Papers (1858-1935) 1884-1935
Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
- Speeches and Writings (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Autobiography (Box-folder 7:169)
  - Autobiography (Box-folder 7:170)
  - Autobiography (Box-folder 7:171)
  - Autobiography (Box-folder 7:172)
  - Autobiography (Box-folder 7:173)
  - Autobiography (Box-folder 7:174)
  - Autobiography (Box-folder 7:175)
  - Autobiography (Box-folder 7:176)
  - Autobiography (Box-folder 7:177)
- Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 5:227)
  - 178. Johnson, Malinda (Box-folder 8:178)
  - Johnson, Malinda (Copy) (Box-folder 8:179)
  - Johnson, Henry (Box-folder 8:180)
  - Johnson, William H. & Nannie Brewer Johnson (Box-folder 8:181)
  - Johnson, Nannie B. (Box-folder 8:182)
  - Johnson, Nannie B. (Box-folder 8:183)
  - Allen, Lucinda P. (Box-folder 8:184)
  - Baxton, Katy (Box-folder 8:186)
  - Bolling, (Rev.) Richard (Box-folder 8:186)
  - Boston, Margaret K. (Box-folder 8:187)
  - Browne, Maggie (Box-folder 8:188)
  - Chaplain, Grace (Box-folder 8:189)
  - Claiborne, Mrs. (Box-folder 8:190)
  - Clark, Mrs. & Daughter (Box-folder 8:191)
  - Clarke, Jr., George W. (Box-folder 8:192)
  - Cole, Effie (Box-folder 8:193)
  - Conrad, Daisy (Box-folder 8:194)
  - Downing, G. (Box-folder 8:195)
  - Farley, Tom (Box-folder 8:196)
  - Forbes, Alexander (Box-folder 8:197)
  - Fox, Ms. (Box-folder 8:198)
  - Gilpin, (Mrs.) Alberta (Box-folder 8:199)
  - Groves, C. (Box-folder 8:200)
  - Harris, Mabel A. (Box-folder 8:201)
  - Hayden, Dellia (Box-folder 8:202)
  - Harris, Octavia Fels (Box-folder 8:203)
  - Holmes, (Mrs.) Jeanette M. (Box-folder 8:204)
  - James, Andrew (Box-folder 8:205)
  - Jarratt, (Mrs.) Nanny (child) (Box-folder 8:206)
  - Jeffries, Mr. and Mrs. (Box-folder 8:207)
  - Jenkins, (Mrs.) Catharine (Box-folder 8:208)
  - Johns, A. (Box-folder 8:209)
  - Johnson, Leonard & Wife (Box-folder 8:210)
  - Johnson, (Mrs.) Margaret (Box-folder 8:211)
  - Johnson, Merr (Box-folder 8:212)
  - Johnson, Richard (Box-folder 8:213)
  - Johnson, Robert (Box-folder 8:214)
  - Johnston, James Hugo, II. (Box-folder 215)
  - Johnston, (Mrs.) (Mother of James Hugo Johnston, Sr.) (Box-folder 8:216)
  - Jones, (Mrs.) Charities (Box-folder 8:217)
  - Jones, (Mrs.) Elizabeth (Box-folder 8:218)
  - Jones, (Mrs.) Freeman (Box-folder 8:219)
  - Jones, (Mrs.) Robert (Box-folder 8:220)
  - Jones, (Mrs.) Robert (Box-folder 8:221)
  - Jones, Ruth A. (Box-folder 8:222)
  - Jordon, (Mrs.) Alice (Box-folder 8:223)
  - Kennard, Mr. & Mrs. Richard (Box-folder 8:224)
  - Kerr, Augustus (Box-folder 8:225)
  - Kountze, Barbara S. (Box-folder 8:226)
  - Lewis, Herbert & Marie (Box-folder 8:227)
  - Lindsay, Anna Laura (Box-folder 8:228)
  - Ms. Lizzie (Box-folder 8:229)
  - Ms. Lois Anne (Box-folder 8:230)
  - Manson, John (Children) (Box-folder 9:231)
  - Manson, Rachel (Box-folder 9:232)
  - Martin, Ruby (Box-folder 9:233)
  - Martin, Dr. Randolph (Box-folder 9:234)
  - Major, James A. (Box-folder 9:235)
  - Mount Pleasant Church (Box-folder 9:236)
  - McLin, Anna & Mary (Box-folder 9:237)
  - Owens, Emanuel & Family (Box-folder 9:238)
  - Page, I. S. (Box-folder 9:239)
  - Parker, William T. (Box-folder 9:240)
  - Phillips, Clay & wife (Box-folder 9:241)
  - Pleasanta, (Mrs.) Corinne R. (Box-folder 9:242)
  - Pollard, (Mrs.) Eunice R. (Box-folder 9:243)
  - Putney, Lucy (Box-folder 9:244)
  - Relaford, (Mrs.) Mary Ellen (Box-folder 9:245)
  - Relaford, V. H. (Box-folder 9:246)
  - Relaford, William R. (Box-folder 9:247)
  - Robinson, Anna Belle (Box-folder 9:248)
  - Robinson, (Mrs.) Rebecca (Box-folder 9:249)
  - Robinson, (Mrs.) (Box-folder 9:250)
  - Rountze, Hillard Cato (Box-folder 9:251)
  - San Jose Mission (Box-folder 9:252)
  - Scotland, Alice (Box-folder 9:253)
  - Scott, A. E. (Box-folder 9:254)
  - Scott, James L. (Box-folder 9:255)
  - Shields, Emma (Box-folder 9:256)
  - Simpson, (Mr.) (Box-folder 9:257)
  - Smith, Helen Cralle (Box-folder 9:258)
  - Smith, Rosa Wilson (Box-folder 9:259)
  - Snell, Pearl, Eveline (Box-folder 9:260)
  - Sutton, S. J. (Box-folder 9:261)
  - Swann, (Mrs.) Elizabeth (Box-folder 9:262)
  - Texas, (Mrs.) Sutton (Box-folder 9:263)
  - Troy, (Rev.) (Box-folder 9:264)
  - V.S.U. - First Faculty and Class (Box-folder 9:265)
  - Watts, Robert (Box-folder 9:266)
  - Williams, (Rev.) Henry (Funeral) (Box-folder 9:267)
  - Williams, (Rev.) Henry (Funeral) (Box-folder 9:268)
  - Williams, (Mrs.) (Box-folder 9:269)
  - Williams, (Mrs.) (Box-folder 9:270)
  - Williams, (Mrs.) (Box-folder 9:271)
  - Wilkerson, Elenora King (Box-folder 9:272)
  - Wilson, Mrs. Nannie J. (Box-folder 9:273)
  - Wilson, Jefferson (Box-folder 9:274)
  - Wilson, Jefferson (Box-folder 9:275)
  - Winfield, Richard (Box-folder 9:276)
  - Wisher, (Elder) (Box-folder 9:277)
  - Worsham Family Home (Box-folder 9:278)
  - Word, Mrs. Adeline (Box-folder 9:279)
  - Unidentified Subjects n.d., 125 photos (Box-folder 10-12:405)
  - Militia Photographs
    - Johnson, William Henry (Box-folder 12:406)
    - Johnson, William Henry (Box-folder 12:407)
    - Stevens, J. C. S. (Box-folder 12:408)
    - Stevens, J. C. S. (Box-folder 12:409)
    - Johnson, William Henry (Box-folder 12:410)
    - Gould, Edwards, W. (Box-folder 12:411)
    - Unidentified Individual, four photos (Box-folder 12:412-415)
    - Unidentified Troopers, two photos (Box-folder 12:416-417)
    - Johnson, William H. & Sergeant (Box-folder 12:418)
    - Stevens, J. C. S. & William H. Johnson (Box-folder 12:419)
    - Company on Parade/ Prussian Style Uniforms (Box-folder 12:420)
    - Battalion on Parade (Box-folder 12:421)
    - Battalion Officers & N. C. O. s (Box-folder 12:422)
    - Battalion on Parade (Box-folder 12:423)
    - Battalion Officers, three photos (Box-folder 12:424-426)
    - Spanish American War Veterans Meeting, two photos (Box-folder 12:427-428)
  - Gillfield Baptist Photos
    - Henry William & Steve Jordan/Bible Class at Gillfield Baptist Church (Box-folder 12:429)
    - Gillfield Adult Sunday School Class (Box-folder 12:430)
    - Gillfield Church Members, two photos (Box-folder 12:431-432)
    - Gillfield Sunday School (Box-folder 12:433)
    - Gillfield Church Members (Box-folder 12:434)
  - Johnson at work, home, school, and the farm
    - Johnson at work, three photos (Box-folder 12:435-437)
    - William Henry Johnson (Box-folder 12:438)
    - Home 1151 Rome Street (Box-folder 12:439)
    - School Interior (Box-folder 12:440)
    - Schools (Box-folder 12:441)
    - Farm Scene, two photos (Box-folder 12:442-443)
    - Work Scene (Box-folder 12:444)
  - Glass Types Framed (Box 13)
- Printed Memorabilia
  - Printers Blocks (Box 14)
  - Announcement-Literary and Musical Program 1929 (Box-folder 15:445)
  - Announcement-Bethany Baptist 1904 (Box-folder 15:446)
  - Announcement-Farmers Conference n.d. (Box-folder 15:447)
  - Announcement-First Baptist Church Anniversary 1918 (Box-folder 15:448)
  - Announcement-Shiloh Baptist Sunday School 1923 (Box-folder 15:449)
  - Announcement-Colored Cemetery 1925 (Box-folder 15:450)
  - Broadsides-Gillfield Baptist Sabbath School 1905 (Box-folder 15:451)
  - Broadsides-Henry Williams at Gillfield n.d. (Box-folder 15:452)
  - Cards-Thank You (Box-folder 15:453)
  - Certificates-Bethany Baptist n.d. (Box-folder 12:454)
  - Certificates-Boy Scouts 1929 (Box-folder 15:455)
  - Certificates-Gillfield 1919 (Box-folder 15:456)
  - Certificates-Gold Coin Club 1907 (Box-folder 15:457)
  - Certificates-Teaching Certificate 1907 (Box-folder 15:458)
  - Certificates-Teaching Certificate 1919 (Box-folder 15:459)
  - Certificates-Membership to NAACP 1933 (Box-folder 15:460)
  - Invitations-Hampton Normal And Agricultural Institute 1895, 1896, 1915, 1916, 1917, 1922, 1925, 1926, 1927, 1928, 1930 (Box-folder 15:461)
  - Invitations-Howard University 1928 (Box-folder 15:462)
  - Invitations-Peabody 1921 (Box-folder 15:463)
  - Invitations-Peabody 1924 (Box-folder 15:464)
  - Invitations-Virginia State 1926 (Box-folder 15:465)
  - Invitations-Ugly Club 1886 (Box-folder 15:466)
  - Pageants-Boy Scouts 1930 (Box-folder 15:467)
  - Pamphlets-Petersburg Colored Association n.d. (Box-folder 15:468)
  - Program-Jones Street School Play 1910 (Box-folder 15:469)
  - Programs-37th Anniversary Bethany Baptist 1925 (Box-folder 15:470)
  - Programs-Bishop Payne 1911 (Box-folder 15:471)
  - Programs-Virginia Normal Debate 1918 (Box-folder 15:472)
  - Programs-Emancipation Program at Peabody 1932 (Box-folder 15:473)
  - Programs-Garden Club 1931 (Box-folder 15:474)
  - Programs-Gillfield 1903 (Box-folder 15:475)
  - Programs-Gillfield 1904 (Box-folder 15:476)
  - Programs-Grant Parade 1897 (Box-folder 15:477)
  - Programs-School Improvement League 1910 (Box-folder 15:478)
  - Programs-Negro Organizational Society 1914 (Box-folder 15:479)
  - Programs-Peabody High School 1927 (Box-folder 15:480)
  - Programs-YMCA (Petersburg) n.d. (Box-folder 15:481)
  - Programs-Piedmont Sanatorium 1924 (Box-folder 15:482)
  - Programs-AMEZ 1912 (Box-folder 15:483)
  - Programs-Virginia Federation of Colored Women 1934 (Box-folder 15:484)
  - Programs-Williamsburg 1919 (Box-folder 15:485)
  - Programs-Presidents Day Virginia State 1925 (Box-folder 15:486)
  - Tickets-Colored Agricultural and Industrial Association 15:1887 (Box-folder 15:487)
  - Restaurant Menu-John Brewer's Restaurant n.d. (Box-folder 15:488)
  - YMCA (Petersburg) 1893 (Box-folder 15:489)
  - Anniversary Program 1928 (Box-folder 15:490)
  - Programs-Virginia Teacher Association 1906 (Box-folder 15:491)
  - Program-Benefit Entertainment 1895 (Box-folder 15:492)
  - Tickets-Gillfield 1895, 1897, 1901 (Box-folder 493)
  - Tickets-Jones Street School 1910 (Box-folder 15:494)
  - Programs-Lindsay Treble Clef Club 1934 (Box-folder 15:495)
  - Five Sunday School Pins from Gillfield n.d. (Box-folder 15:496)
  - Oversized photos, framed. Photo Albums. (Box 15-A)
- Scrapbooks, Contains programs, cards, photographs, and some correspondence. (Box 16-19)
- Artifacts, Contains household articles, toys and games; two boxes of military items and two footlockers; also the sheath for a dress saber. (Box 20-25)
- Oversize, Maps and photos.
  - Parade Route for the Grant Inaugural Parade (1897), Parade Route for the Peoples Cemetery 1897 (Folder 497)
  - Broadside-An Hour in Old Gillfield 1915 (Folder 498)